# RAFAEL ROCHA

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

□ rafaelmarianorocha@gmail.com □ rafrocha.github.io/ □ 778.323.3909 □ Vancouver, BC

in rafael-mariano-da-rocha-b0005742/ O rafrocha

## **SUMMARY**

I am passioned about using logic to solve problems. Coding is a hobby and a career. Efficiency and user experience combined with solutions that anticipate future needs have been my focus since starting this journey. Moved from Brazil to beautiful British Columbia in 2014. When away form the keyboard, I love playing sports and travelling.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Lighthouse Labs

Project Evaluator · Feb. 2019 to Current · Vancouver, BC

As a project evaluator, I am responsible for providing feedback and grading bootcamp students throughout their program and projects.

#### Agreement Express

Software Developer · Sept. 2018 to Current · Vancouver, BC

Agreement Express is the global leader in SaaS-based contract management software for the financial services industry. I am part of a team that builds responsive landing pages for payments companies.

We also build dynamic Scorecards for Merchant and Owner analysis through various API integrations services.

Stack: React.js, Redux, Java, SQL

## **EDUCATION**

Lighthouse Labs · July 2018 to Sept. 2018 Diploma Web Development 2018 Full-Time Web Development Bootcamp

Lighthouse Labs · Jan. 2018 to Feb. 2018

Part-time Course Front-end Fundamentals 2018

PUCRS · Jan. 2009 to Dec. 2013

Bachelors Business Adminsitration 2013

### **SKILLS**

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, Ruby, Java

**FRAMEWORKS/LIBRARIES:** React.js, jQuery, Ajax, Express, Redux, Node.js **DATABASE/BUILDERS:** PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Webpack, Babel

LANGUAGES: Portuguese, Spanish

## **PROJECTS**

#### Horde Land

Aug. 2018 to Sept. 2018

Online multi-player shooting 2D multi-map game. Built without any game engines. HTML Canvas and Vanilla Javascript for game logic. React for UI rendering (Chat, Scoreboard, activity log, game announcements). Node and Express server. Using Scoket.io.

#### Chatty App

July 2018 to Aug. 2018

Multi-user messaging client built using React with a Node and Express server backend. Development focused on implementing WebSockets and the React framework.

#### Bendito App

Aug. 2018 to Aug. 2018

A responsive, team-built food-ordering and order management application that communicates with clients via SMS. Stack: JS, PSQL, Express, Twilio, Ajax, jQuery and HTML/CSS/SASS.

## **VOLUNTEERING**

Lighthouse Labs · Javascript Seminar Mentor

Mar. 2019 to Current · Vancouver, BC

Volunteering as a mentor in various Javascript Seminars, helping students and prospects learn the basics of Javascript.